<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <rdf:Description>
      <dc:title>Myths of the Cherokee</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>James Mooney (1861–1921)</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Project Gutenberg, Urbana, Illinois, USA., 2014-05-11</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2014-05-11</dc:date>
      <dc:rights>This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online at www.gutenberg.org.
This eBook is produced by the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at www.pgdp.net.
Scans for this book are available from the Internet Archive (copy 1, 2). The same text also appears as part of the Nineteenth Annual Report of the Bureau of American Ethnology, which is also available from the Internet Archive (copy 1). Some of the folk tales appeared already in 1888 as “Myths of the Cherokees” in the Journal of American Folk-lore (copy 1).
The cover design is based on the original cover of the Nineteenth Annual Report, to which is added the title, author, and year of publication.
This ebook uses Cherokee script in Unicode encoding. You can install a Cherokee font from the website of the Cherokee Nation. The Tsulehisanvhi font it offers closely resembles the original letter designs, as prepared in 1827 for printing a national paper, the Cherokee Phœnix.
</dc:rights>
      <dc:subject>Cherokee Indians</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Indians of North America</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Cherokee Indians -- History</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Cherokee language</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Trail of Tears, 1838-1839</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Cherokee Indians -- North Carolina</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Folklore, Indian</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>A large collection of Cherokee folklore, collected by the author. The introduction provides a sketch of the history of the Cherokee people.</dc:description>
      <dc:identifier>pg:45634</dc:identifier>
   </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
